[ Suspenseful instrumental music plays ]
[ Music intensifies ]
[ Silence ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Door hinges creak ]
[ Bo screams ]
[ Insects chirping ]
[ Door hinges creak , door slams ]
Where are they ?
I don 't know .
Morgan : Dad !
Uncle Merrill !
Dad !
Morgan !
[ Birds cawing ]
[ Rapid footsteps ]
Bo ? Bo ?
Bo , where 's Morgan ?
Bo ?
Are you in my dream , too ?
- - This is not a dr- - Morgan : Dad !
Hey ...
Honey ...
[ Panting ]
Morgan ? What 's happening ?
The dogs were barking - - woke us up .
[ Dogs barking in distance ]
Are you hurt ?
I think God did it .
Did what , Morgan ?
[ Barking continues , birds cawing ]
[ Barking ]
Look , Lee , I don 't even care if it was him ,
Ad you can just have a word with him ,
and that 'd be enough for me .
See , it was strange finding the crops that way .
The kids were confused by it ,
and , uh , it 'd sure take the strangeness away
if I know it was just Lionel and the Wolfington brothers messing around ,
that 's all .
At the movies ?
Are you sure ?
[ Sighing ] All right , then .
Uh , thanks for your patience , Lee .
Yeah . Bye .
[ Telephone beeps ]
Houdini peed . I think he 's sick .
Why don 't you take him outside ? I 'll call Dr. Crawford .
He doesn 't treat animals .
Well , he 'll know what to do .
[ Chain rattles ]
[ Door hinges creak ; door opens , slams ]
Oh . That was quick , Caroline .
I only called you folks two hours ago .
Old Mrs. Kendleman twisted her ankle ,
as she puts it , diving for her life
when a bunch of school kids rode down the sidewalk on skateboards .
She went down to Thornton 's store this morning
and started spitting on the now skateboards .
Spitting !
By the time I got there ,
Mrs. Kendleman had sprayed the whole damned place .
Ad she must have had a cold or something .
I 'm telling you , I won 't eat for a week .
[ Sighs deeply ]
So , what happened to your crops ?
[ Sizzling ]
Dad 's gonna burn these again .
It 's contaminated .
You don 't even know what that word means .
It 's not contaminated .
It 's just tap water . Pour it in his bowl .
It tastes funny .
It does not .
Ad besides , he licks his butt every day .
I don 't think he 'll mind .
[ Barks ]
[ Growling ]
Houdini ?
Bo , don 't run .
What 's wrong , boy ?
[ Growling continues ]
Stop it , Houdini .
[ Barks ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Snarling ]
Caroline : Look at where it 's bent over , Father .
Graham : it 's not broken .
Now , what kind of machine can bend a stalk of corn over without breaking it ?
Can 't be by hand . It 's too perfect .
It doesn 't sound much like Lionel Prichard and the Wolfington brothers .
They can 't take a piss
without wetting the front of their pants .
I don 't think anyone else around here has had any problems .
I was over at Theo Henry 's farm yesterday afternoon ,
and he would have mentioned something .
Why were you at Theo 's place ?
Some animals around the county have been acting funny - -
and some of them violent .
What is it , a virus ?
I don 't think so , Father .
They 're more edgy , you know , and alert .
It 's almost like they act when they smell a predator around - -
peeing on themselves and everything .
[ Birds cawing ]
Caroline ...
please stop calling me " Father . "
What 's wrong ?
I don 't hear my children .
[ Sniffles ]
He fell on me .
He wanted to kill Bo .
[ Sniffling and wheezing ]
[ Air hisses ] - - [ Inhales deeply ]
[ Exhales deeply ]
Did he hurt you ?
No .
I 'm so sorry , Morgan .
Where were you ?
Houdini 's sick .
Tie Isabel up to the back of the shod , please ,
and make sure the knot 's very tight .
[ Insects chirping ]
[ Gasps ]
What 's the matter ?
There 's a monster outside my room .
Can I have a glass of water ?
What 's wrong with the water next to your bed ?
It tastes old .
[ Breathes deeply ]
[ Sighs softly ]
What are you thinking about ?
Why do you talk to Mom when you 're by yourself ?
Makes me feel better .
Does she ever answer back ?
No .
She never answers me either .
[ Sighs deeply ]
[ Inhales sharply ]
What ?
[ Whispering ] Lionel Prichard and the Wolfington brothers are back .
[ Whispering ] It 's time for an ass-wh upping .
This is not an intelligent way to approach this .
Lee is a friend of mine . This is his son .
Yeah , we 'll be doing Lee a favor .
All right , listen - - we both go outside ,
mover around the house in opposite directions .
We act crazy , insane with anger - -
make them crap in their pants ,
force them around till we meet up on the other side .
Explain " act crazy . "
You know , curse and stuff .
You want me to curse ?
You don 't mean it . It 's just for show .
What ?
Well , it won 't be convincing .
It doesn 't sound natural when I curse .
Just make noises , then .
Explain " noises . "
Are you gonna do this or what ?
No , I 'm not .
All right , you want them stealing something in the house next time ?
On the count of three
1 ... - - All right .
2 ... 3 !
[ Door hinges creak ]
Aaah ! I 'm insane with anger !
We 're gonna beat your ass , bitch !
[ Clattering ]
We 're gonna tear your head off !
I 'm losing my mind !
[ Rapid footsteps ]
It 's time for an ass-wh upping !
[ Both panting ]
I cursed .
I heard .
[ Rustling ]
How did he got ...
[ Rustling continues ]
Are you sure this is Lionel Prichard ?
[ Clattering ]
[ Squeaking ]
[ Birds chirping ]
Caroline : You like that ?
You got an old baby monitor around ?
Bo had an old baby monitor .
You can use Bo 's baby monitor as a walkie-talkie .
- - You can ? - - Mm-hmm .
It only works one way , but that 'll do fine .
[ Machinery whirring on television ]
That is , until someone gets you an old walkie-talkie left over at the station .
Man : Stop ! it 's hideous !
Woman : Get it off !
I-I know what to do .
[ Woman shuddering ]
Hey , Bo ...
turn that down till Officer Paski leaves .
Dey-da !
[ Laser gun fires ]
[ Volume decreases ]
You 're too old to still be doing this .
You take a glass of water , and you finish it .
Now , what 's wrong with this one ?
It has dust in it .
This one ?
A hair .
Morgan took a sip , and it has his amebas in it .
My turn .
So , how are you , Merrill ?
Fine .
How is work at the gas station ?
Stimulating .
[ Chuckles ]
I never got a chance to tell you ,
but I-I thought your moving in here with your brother after - -
it was a nice thing to do .
Well , I don 't think I 'm helping much .
You are .
Sorry , .
Okay , so far I have , " It was very dark . "
Yes , it was .
You can 't describe him at all ?
Don 't you think that 's kind of odd ?
A little .
I don 't know whether to look for a giant or a midget .
No , he definitely wasn 't a midget .
Okay .
So he was tall ?
I-I would say so , yes .
Probably .
Over 6 feet ?
It was very dark .
Yes , it was .
How certain are you that this was a male ?
Oh , I don 't know - - I don 't know any girls who could run like that .
I don 't know , Merrill .
I 've seen some of those women on the Olympics .
They can run like the wind .
This guy got on our roof in , like , a second .
O-Our roof is 10 feet high .
They have women 's high jumping in the Olympics .
They got these Scandinavian women
who can jump clean over me .
Caroline , I know you 're making a point here ,
but I just don 't know what it is .
A out-of-town woman stopped by the diner yesterday afternoon
and started yelling and cussing
because they didn 't have her favorite cigarettes
at the vending machine .
She scared a couple of the customers .
No one 's seen her since .
Ad my point is ,
we don 't know anything about the person you saw ,
and we should just keep all possibilities available .
[ Footsteps approach ]
Dad , where 's the remote ?
I don 't know , baby .
Why don 't you check in the sofa cushions ?
Excluding the possibility
that a female Scandinavian Olympian
was running around outside our house last night ,
what else might be a possibility ?
I 'm not done asking questions ,
and I don 't appreciate sarcasm .
Do you two have anyone
who might have a grudge " or something against you " - -
maybe a-a church member
" who " - - " who might " not have liked
the fact that you left the church ?
I don 't think so .
Okay , I was out of line
with the whole female - Scandinavian-Olympian thing .
it 's just I 'm pretty strong ,
and I 'm pretty fact .
And I was running as fact as I could ,
and this guy , he was - - he was just toying with us .
There 's only food under the sofa .
Baby , why don 't you
just change the channel on the television ?
I did .
Ad ?
Same show 's on every station .
Every station ?
Graham : Bo , turn up the volume .
Crop signs first emerged in the late ' 70s
with renewed interact in extraterrestrial life .
They died out by the early ' 80s ,
dismissed as hoaxes .
This now resurgence is wholly different .
The speed and the quantity in which it has appeared
implies the coordination of hundreds of individuals
over many countries .
[ Indistinct conversations ]
There are only a limited number of explanations .
Either this is one of the most elaborate hoaxes over created ,
or basically ...
it 's for real .
[ Air hisses ] - - [ Inhales deeply ]
Extraterrestrials .
What in God 's name is going on ?
I did some research after I saw your crops .
Two or three guys can make a design the size of the one in your field overnight
using just boards and ropes .
Really ?
That 's how these things have been done in the past .
But there are so many now .
How could so many people be in on it ?
I can 't think straight .
I 'm - - I 'm gonna go back to the station
and have a cup of Edgar 's coffee and - - and try to think clear .
Ad after that , I 'll ...
I might make some calls .
But I 'll tell you something - - what I said in there , it still goes .
Your - - your family has been through a lot .
Ad the last thing these children need to do
is worry , about some crazy things happening in the world .
Now , take them into town
and got their minds and your mind on everyday things , hmm ?
Good medicine .
That 's good advice .
Ad you take care of yourself ...
Graham .
[ Engine turns over ]
Man on TV : . The footage you 're watching was shot yesterday afternoon
by a 34-year-old local cameraman in Bangalore
a southern city of India .
it 's the 18th reported crop sign
found in that country in the last 72 hours .
Uncle Merrill , will you turn on the radio ?
Woman on radio : They are signs intended " to be seen from the sky " - -
[ Radio turns off ]
No radio either . Just for a while .
[ Sighs ]
[ Brakes squeak ]
Book money ?
Sure .
Just one .
Bo back for pizza in 15 .
Carl : it 's just a bunch of crock
They 're trying to sell sodas . it 's plain and simple .
Been watching these reports since morning .
I have seen 12 soda commercials so far - -
12 !
You have any books on extraterrestrials ?
Now , don 't tell me you believe this horse manure .
As a matter of fact , I think we have one .
Came by mistake in a shipment - -
decided to keep it for the city people .
Last row , third book on the left , honey .
Man on radio : Why is no one saying the obvious ?
These are just copycats .
Someone somewhere does the first one ...
Woman : It was asthma medicine , right , Father ?
For Morgan Hess .
Ad it 's not " Father " anymore .
ln less than an hour , a couple hundred people got the same brilliant idea ,
and here we are , on the verge of mass hysteria .
Can I ask you a favor , Father ?
I need to clear my conscience .
Will you listen to me ?
Tracey ... I am not a reverend anymore .
I haven 't been for six months .
You know this .
[ Voice breaking ] All this stuff on TV - -
two girls came in here talking about the end of the world - -
I 'm just a little scared . [ Sniffles ]
Please , I need to clear my conscience .
I 've got it figured .
You do ?
I 've had two separate folks tell me
there have been strangers around these parts last couple nights .
Can 't tell what they look like
'cause they 're staying in the shadows - - covert like .
Nobody 's been hurt , mind you .
Ad that 's the giveaway .
I seen .
it 's called " probing . "
it 's a military procedure .
You send out a reconnaissance group - -
very small - - to check things out .
Not to engage but to evaluate the situation - -
evaluate the level of danger ,
make sure things are all clear .
Clear for what ?
For the rect of them .
Yeah ?
You got a pamphlet or something I can read ?
Sure .
Thanks .
You didn 't used to play baseball , did ya ?
Shit , I know you . You 're Merrill Hess .
I was there the day you hit that 507-footer
over the left-field wall - - set the record .
Man , that thing had a motor on it .
It 's still the record , right ?
Got the bat at home o-on the wall .
You 've got two minor-league home-run records , don 't ya ?
Five .
Why weren 't you in the pros making stacks of cash
and getting your toes licked by beautiful women ?
'Cause he has another record most people don 't know about .
He has the minor-league strikeout record .
Hello , Lionel .
Merrill 's a class-A screw-up .
He would just swing that bat as hard as he could every time .
Didn 't matter what the coaches said ,
didn 't matter who was on base .
He would just whip that bat through the air as hard as he could .
Looked like a lumberjack chopping down a tree .
Merrill here has more strike outs than any two players .
You really got the strike out record ?
Felt wrong not to swing .
It 's contaminated .
Carl , there 's something wrong with our water .
Your water 's fine .
Bo has this thing about her drinking water .
She had it her whole life .
It 's like a tick people have , except it 's not a tick .
Is that right ?
[ Pounds table ] Carl : 13 !
# # Don 't give me that so-so-soda # #
# # That same old cola # #
# # I wanna pop # #
- - " # # Pop , pop " I wanna ... Shasta # # - - I 'll take it .
Tracey : . I cursed 37 times last week .
I said the " F " word a couple times , but mostly ... " shits "
and ... " bastards . "
Is " douche bag " a curse ?
I suppose that would depend on its usage .
How about , " John , you 're a douche bag for kissing Barbara " ?
It 's a curse .
Then it 's not 37 . It 's 71 .
Pharmacy crowded ?
I don 't want any one of you
spending time with Tracey Abernathy alone .
Is that understood ?
[ Breathes deeply ]
Is that him ?
Yeah .
[ Car door closes , engine turns over ]
Who is he ?
[ Tires squeal ]
[ Insects chirping ]
[ Car approaches ]
[ Brakes squeak ]
[ Static ]
Merrill : What is it ?
Graham : it 's Bo 's baby monitor .
I found it in the basement .
I 'm gonna use it as a walkie-talkie .
[ Droning ]
What if it 's catching a signal from them ?
It 's not .
But it wasn 't working .
Morgan , this crop stuff is about a bunch of nerds
who never had a girlfriend in their lives .
They 're , like , 30 , and they work up little codes together ,
and they analyze Greek mythology and make up secret societies
where other guys who never had girlfriends before can join in .
They do stupid crap like this to feel special .
It 's a scam .
Nerds were doing it 25 years ago ,
and now nerds are doing it again .
It 's just static , Morgan , all right .
Turn it up . See .
[ Volume increases ]
[ Droning continues ]
It 's a code .
Why can 't they got girlfriends ?
Can I seen that , please ?
[ Static , droning continue ]
It 's noise .
It 's broken , Morgan . It 's just gonna keep doing this .
Maybe some now batteries ...
We might lose the signal .
This is exactly what the nerds want .
I 'm getting out now .
[ Droning continues , volume increases ]
Nobody mover .
Voices . Did you hear that ?
Not English , though .
You heard the voices , right , Uncle Merrill ?
I heard them , Morgan .
[ Droning ]
Probably picking up another baby monitor .
That 's right .
[ Pitch fluctuates ]
Let me seen it .
[ High-pitched droning ]
Stop !
[ Warbling ]
[ Volume decreases ]
See , this is why we 're not watching TV .
People got obsessed .
I 'm letting go now .
Bo : No , Dad !
Morgan : Don 't do it !
You 'll lose the signal .
Don 't lot go .
It gets clearer the higher you hold it .
Merrill : I got it .
Bo , honey , I don 't want you climbing on the car .
Come here .
[ Volume increases ]
[ Panting ]
[ Droning , trilling ]
Stop !
There 's two of them talking .
[ Droning , trilling ]
[ Static ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Ball clanging ]
[ Isabel barks , whines ]
[ Barking continues ]
[ Barking ]
- - [ Snarls ] - - " [ Gasps ] "
[ Barking continues ]
[ Chain rattling ]
[ Whining ]
Isabel , you 're gonna feel very silly
when this turns out to be all just make-believe .
[ Whining continues ]
[ Creaks ]
[ Barking continues ]
- - " [ Trilling ] " - - [ Gasps ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Echoing ] You 're wasting your time here !
I 'm not gonna report this or anything you do to my crops
to the news or TV or anybody !
You 're not going to got famous !
[ Trilling ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Corn stalks rustling ]
[ Trills ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Panting ]
[ Dishes clanking , water splashing ]
[ Giggling ]
[ Sighs deeply ]
Okay .
Let 's turn on the TV .
[ Clicks , television humming ]
Man on TV : . It first appeared 52 minutes ago .
Mexico City officials as well as U.S. officials
have confirmed that these are not aircraft
from either government 's air force .
The first sighting was made by an Air Mexico 747
en route from Mazatlán to New York
as the unidentified crafts entered Mexico City air space .
They were not detected by radar by either country .
[ Siren walls on TV ] - - The nerds were right .
We have to tape this .
My ballot recital .
Listen , Bo , this is very important .
Everything people have written about in science books is going to change .
The history of the world 's future is on the TV right now .
We need to record this so you can show " your " children this tape
and say you were there .
For your children , Bo .
My ballot recital .
Dad !
Find another tape .
[ Videotape clattering ]
[ Siren continues ]
Uncle Merrill , I 'm using your tape .
Man on TV : . You are seeing a live feed
from our affiliate down here in Mexico City .
This image has not been adjusted or enhanced in any way .
What you 're seeing is real .
it 's unbelievable .
- - [ Wheezing ] - - " Everything they wrote " in science books
is about to change
I told you .
[ Air hisses ] - - [ Inhales deeply ]
Some people are probably thinking
this is the end of the world .
That 's true .
Do you think it could be ?
Yes .
How can you say that ?
That wasn 't the answer you wanted ?
Couldn 't you pretend to be like you used to be ?
[ Exhales sharply ] Give me some comfort .
People break down into two groups
when they experience something lucky .
Group number one sees it as more than luck ,
more than coincidence .
They seen it as a sign - -
evidence that there is someone up there
watching out for them .
Group number two sees it as just pure luck ,
a happy turn of chance .
I 'm sure the people in group number two
are looking at those 14 lights in a very suspicious way .
For them , the situation isn 't 50-50 .
Could be bad , could be good .
But deep down ,
they feel that whatever happens ,
they 're on their own .
Ad that fills them with fear .
Yeah , there are those people .
But there 's a whole lot of people in the group number one .
When they seen those 14 lights ,
they 're looking at a miracle .
And deep down , they feel that whatever 's going to happen ,
there 'll be someone there to help them .
Ad that fills them with hope .
See , what you have to ask yourself is , what kind of person are you ?
Are you the kind who sees signs , sees miracles ?
Or do you believe that people just got lucky ?
Or look at the question " this way " - -
is it possible that there are no coincidences ?
I was at this party once .
I 'm on the couch with Randa McKinney . [ Clicks tongue ]
[ Exhales sharply ] She was just sitting there
looking beautiful , staring at me .
I go to lean in and kiss her ...
[ Laughing ] and I realize I have gum in my mouth .
So I turn , take out the gum ,
stuff it in a paper cup next to the sofa ,
and turn around .
Randa McKinney throws up all over herself .
[ Chuckles softly ]
I know the second it happened it was a miracle .
I could have been kissing her when she throw up .
That would have scarred me for life .
I may never have recovered .
[ Laughs ]
I 'm a miracle man .
Those lights are a miracle .
There you go .
So , which type are you ?
Do you feel comforted ?
Yeah , I do .
Then what does it matter ?
I never told you the last words
that Colleen said before they lot her die .
She said , " See . "
Then her eyes glazed a bit .
And then she said , " Swing away . "
You know why she said that ?
Because the nerve endings in her brain were firing as she died ,
and some random memory of us at one of your baseball games just popped into her head .
There is no one watching out for us , Merrill .
We are all on our own .
[ Siren walls ]
[ Keys jingle , engine turns off ]
What do you know ?
Well , there was an accident - - drunk driving , they weren 't sure - -
He wasn 't drunk . Ray fell asleep at the wheel .
- - Is he okay ? - - Yeah .
That was the first thing Colleen asked , too .
She 's talking . What ambulance is she in ?
She 's not in an ambulance , Father .
[ Floorboards squeak ]
For the kids ' protection .
All they were doing was watching TV from 5 : 00 a.m.
I felt like they were getting obsessed , like you said .
They should be playing furry , furry , rabbit or tea party or something .
What 's furry , furry , rabbit ?
It 's a game , isn 't it ?
Anyway , they closed the schools .
Ad there 's been some interacting developments .
What time is it ?
11 : 00 a.m.
They 're gone , but they 're not really gone .
We just can 't seen them .
Early this morning , a bird flow into the area
where the lights were hovering last night .
It stopped dead in the air and fell straight down .
They caught it on tape . They 've been playing it all morning .
The footage looks like the bird flow into a wall in the sky .
They found the bird . His - - his head was crushed in .
They think they have some kind of invisible-shield thing going , I-like an optical illusion .
They 're still there , hovering .
Some people think there 's more of them now ...
All over the place , over us , even .
There 's a theory about the c- - the crop circles .
They could be some kind of - -
some kind of landmark ,
visual mapping system so they could navigate ,
coordinate - -
makes sense .
[ Wind chimes tinkling ]
Morgan : Want to hear a story ?
Bo : Is it true ?
So the aliens can 't read our minds .
Oh .
Oh , of course .
They toll you everything in this book .
It says they 're probably very small , like my height ,
because as their brains develop ,
there was no use for physical development .
It also says they 're probably vegetarians
because they would have realized the benefits of such a diet .
Who wrote this book ?
Scientists who have been persecuted for their beliefs .
That means they 're unemployed .
If you 're gonna make fun of it , then forgot it .
This is serious .
I don 't know what got into me .
There are pictures .
Dr. Bimbu , one of the authors of the book - -
- - Bimbu ? - - Dad .
I just asked his name .
You had a tone .
He said there are two reasons why extraterrestrials would visit us - -
to make contact in the spirit of exploration
and furthering the knowledge of the universe ,
or the other reason - - they 're hostile .
They 've used up all the resources on their planet ,
and they 're looking to harvest our planet next .
Here .
Looks a little like our house , doesn 't it ?
Same windows .
That 's weird .
[ Telephone rings ]
- - [ Gasps ] - - [ Gasps ]
Yeah , oh , yeah .
That 's enough from Dr. Bimbu for now .
Everybody in this house needs to calm down
and eat some fruit or something .
[ Ringing continues ]
Hello ?
Man : Father ?
[ Pulsating tone ]
[ Footsteps approach ]
[ Door hinges creak ]
I 'm going out for a few minutes .
No one leaves this house - - no one .
Merrill : Where you going ?
[ Keys jingle ] - - Ray Reddy 's house .
Why ?
I think he just called here .
[ Door opens , slams ]
Bo : You don 't think something bad will happen ,
do you , Morgan ?
Why ? You have one of your feelings again ?
Is it bad ?
I won 't lot anything bad happen to you .
I don 't want you to die .
Who said I was gonna die ?
[ Knock on door ]
[ Insects chirping ]
[ Insects chirping , door hinges creak ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Pulsating tone ]
Hello , Ray .
What happened ?
I wrote your number down to call you .
It 's been sitting next to the phone for 6 months .
When I know it was inside the house ...
I couldn 't think of any other number to call . I panicked .
Thank you for coming , Father .
You 're welcome , Ray .
I worked so long that night .
I 've never fallen asleep driving before ...
never since .
Don 't .
Most of the ride home ,
there wasn 't a car in sight in either direction .
If I 'd have fallen asleep then ,
I would have ended up in a ditch with a headache .
And it had to be at that " right moment " - -
that 10 , 15 seconds when I passed her walking .
It was like it was meant to be .
I guess if this is the end of the world ,
I 'm screwed , right ?
People who kill reverends ' wives
aren 't exactly ushered to the front of the line in Heaven .
[ Keys jingle ]
[ Engine turns over ]
Wh- - Where are you going , Ray ?
To the lake .
The way I seen it ...
these places marked in crops and such - -
none of them are really near water .
I don 't think they like water .
Can 't be any worse than here .
Did you seen something , Ray ?
I know what I 've done to you .
I made you question your faith .
I 'm truly sorry , for what I 've done to you and yours .
[ Sighs deeply ]
All right .
Ad don 't open my pantry , Father .
I found one of them in there and locked him in .
[ Tires spin ]
Woman on TV : . The startling footage we 're about to show you
was photographed by a 42-year-old , Romero Valadarez .
This video was taken yesterday afternoon
at his son 's 7th birthday
in the city of Passo Fundo , Brazil .
It was sent to the local news bureau there
and sent to us via satellite just a few minutes ago .
All initial opinions are this is genuine .
What you 're about to seen may disturb you .
[ Children shouting indistinctly in Portuguese ]
[ Dogs barking ]
Move , children ! Vámanos !
[ Shouting continues ]
[ Shouting intensifies ]
Oh !
[ Shouting continues ]
[ Tape rewinds ]
[ Shouts in Portuguese ]
[ Rustling , wind whistling ]
[ Rustling stops ]
Hello ?
The police are here . I am with them .
I am a police officer .
I just want to talk with you .
We know all about the hoax .
We already took some of your friends downtown in a paddy wagon .
Just tell us your name and why you did it ,
and we 'll give you the same deal we gave the others .
Don 't throw your life away , son .
[ Sighs ]
[ Knife scrapes ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Scrapes ]
Oh ! Ah !
Oh !
[ Both scream ]
[ Birds chirping ]
[ Dead belt clicks ]
Their skin changes colors .
That 's why we couldn 't seen them that night .
Tell me something , Morgan .
Uh ... in this book of yours ...
did they happen to detail
what would happen if they were hostile ?
Yes .
It said they would probably invade .
They would use ground tactics - - hand-to-hand combat .
They wouldn 't use our technology or fight an airborne battle
'cause they know eventually we would use nuclear weapons .
Then the planet would be useless to them .
How could anyone possibly know that information ? it 's ridiculous .
What else did it say ?
They said there are one of two outcomes of an invasion .
One , they fight and are defeated and have to return again
with full forces hundreds , maybe even thousands , of years later .
What 's two ?
They win .
I 'm sorry , what - - what book is this ?
Is this really happening ?
[ Sighs ]
I heard a theory that , uh ,
they don 't like places near water .
Maybe we 'd be safe from them near a lake or something .
Sounds made-up .
I saw one of them at Ray Reddy 's house .
I can 't be sure ,
but I got the distinct feeling he wanted to harm me .
So ...
we can choose to believe this lake idea , pack up , and go ,
or we can stay here , hide inside our home , wait it out .
We might be overreacting , but I 'm willing to live with that .
Either way , at least we 'll be together .
All those in favor of the lake idea , raise your hand .
Yeah .
All those in favor of home , raise your hand .
Okay .
My vote counts as two .
That 's bullshit ! You 're cheating !
Morgan , calm down .
I got two votes because I represent two parents here .
We don 't know anything yet .
We 'll be safe here anyway .
I don 't want to leave home .
This is where we lived with Mom .
That 's got nothing to do with this .
I change my vote .
You can 't change your vote .
All those in favor of home , raise your hand .
This is ridiculous .
You lose , 3-2 .
[ Sighs deeply ]
We 're going to board up every window in this house .
How do we know boards will do anything ?
Because they seem to have trouble with pantry doors .
[ Sighs deeply ]
[ Wind chimes tinkling ]
[ Door hinges creak ]
[ Corn stalks rustling ]
[ Tinkling , rustling continue ]
[ Soft thud ]
[ Tinkling , rustling intensify ]
Man on TV : . The information we 're receiving
comes from our affiliates across the world .
[ Siren walls on TV , pounding ] Morgan : Dad , Uncle Merrill !
Amman joins Nairobi , Beijing , and Jerusalem
as the latest to confirm the appearance of lights .
There are lights in over 274 cities .
They think it 'll be 400 within the hour .
They 're appearing at or within one mile of crop signs .
They " were " for navigation .
They made a map .
They 're gonna be within a mile of us .
Dad ?
Yes ?
They think these are staged
immediately preceding an attack maneuver .
I was wrong . They 're hostile .
[ Horns honk on TV ]
It 's like " War of the Worlds . "
Man on TV : . Ground forces have been assembled
in countries throughout the globe .
[ Clears throat ]
Hundreds of thousands
have flocked to topless , synagogues , and churches .
[ Indistinct conversations , bell tells ]
God be with us all .
[ Machinery clanking , helicopters whirring on TV ]
I 'm going to got back to the windows .
Hey , you guys okay ?
Some guy had a sign saying it was the end of the world .
Don 't worry , .
You won 't lot anything happen to us , right ?
No way .
I wish you were my dad .
What did you say ?
Don 't you " over " say anything like that again .
Ever .
[ Tinkling ]
There 's too many windows in the bedrooms .
We don 't have enough boards .
We 'll board up the bedroom doors .
Where are we gonna sleep ?
In the family room .
What about Isabel ?
We 'll tie her up in the garage after dinner .
I 'll make some sandwiches .
I want spaghetti .
We 'll just eat fact , Bo .
Spaghetti sounds great .
What do you want , Morgan ?
Anything ?
French toast ...
and mashed potatoes .
Now we 're talking .
How about you , Merrill ?
Chicken teriyaki .
Good choice .
I 'm going to have a cheeseburger with bacon .
Extra bacon . [ Chuckles ]
What 's the matter with everyone ? Eat .
Maybe we should say a prayer .
No .
Why not ?
We 're not saying a prayer .
Bo has a bad feeling .
I had a dream .
We aren 't saying a prayer .
Eat !
I hate you .
That 's fine .
You lot Mom die .
Merrill : Morgan .
I am not wasting one more minute of my life on prayer .
Not one more minute .
Understood ?
[ Bo cries ]
Now we are going to enjoy this meal .
No one can stop us from enjoying this meal , so enjoy it !
- - [ Crying continues ] - - Stop crying !
- - Graham ... - - " Don 't yell at her ! "
[ Crying continues ]
All right , since you 're all not gonna eat .
I 'm gonna try some of everything .
[ Silverware bangs ]
[ Sniffles ]
[ Crying ]
[ Static ]
[ Droning , trilling ]
[ " Off air " signal blaring ]
It 's happening .
[ Insects chirping ]
[ Silence ]
Graham , hurry , .
Did I ever tell you what everyone said
when you were born , Bo ?
You came out of your mama , and you didn 't even cry .
You just opened your eyes ,
and you looked around the room at everybody .
[ Chuckles ] Your eyes were so big and gorgeous .
All the ladies in the room just gasped .
I mean , they literally gasped .
Ad they go , " Oh , she 's like an angel . "
Ad they said , " We 've never seen a baby so beautiful . "
Ad then ... you know what happened ?
They put you on the table to clean you up ,
and you looked up at me and you smiled .
They say babies that young can 't smile .
You smiled .
Let 's go down now .
[ Isabel barking in distance ]
We forgot Isabel .
[ Barking continues ]
[ Growling ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Silence ]
[ Wind chimes tinkling ]
Should we turn off the lights ?
They already know we 're here .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Wind chimes tinkling ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Footsteps continue ]
[ Loud thud ]
[ Thud ]
[ Clattering ]
Dad ...
[ Rapid footsteps ]
Do you know what happened when you were born , Morgan ?
You came out , and your mama kept bleeding ,
so the doctors rushed you out of the room
before I even had time to seen you .
[ Footsteps continue ]
They 're on the roof .
While they were fixing her up ,
all she kept asking about was you .
[ Crash ]
They 're in the house .
I wanted your mama to seen you first
because she had dreamed about you her whole life .
Then she got feeling better , they brought you in ,
and they placed you in her arms ,
and she looked at you , and you looked at her ,
and you just stared at each other for the longest time .
And then she said real soft ,
" Hello , Morgan . I 'm your mama .
You look just how I dreamed . "
[ Breathes deeply ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Clattering ]
[ Rapid footsteps ]
Merrill : The attic door .
Let 's go .
Come on .
We forgot our foil helmets .
Have we got anything to wedge against the door knob ?
They 'll read our minds .
You 're scaring your sister .
I 'm already scared .
[ Trilling ]
Merrill .
I 'm looking !
They 'll know our secret thoughts .
I 'm not ready .
Merrill !
Got it !
[ Light bulb shatters ] - - Dad !
[ Thumping , clattering ]
[ Coughs ]
Where 's Bo ?
I 'm okay .
[ Footsteps , clattering ]
[ Clicks , tuning , static ]
What 's happening out there ?
Graham : I can 't even imagine .
I hope they 're doing better than we are .
We don 't even have helmets .
[ Pounding on door ]
They 're only making noises . They 're not trying to got in .
Why would they do that ?
They want our attention on the door ?
[ Pounding continues ]
They 're distracting us .
From what ?
The book says they 're probably very good problem solvers .
They 'll find a way in .
[ Pounding continues ]
Morgan , give me your flashlight .
They used to pour coal down in this basement .
There 's a coal chute in here .
[ Pounding continues ]
I can feel air .
Me too !
It 's getting stronger .
I 'm close .
[ Wind whistling ]
What ?
Hold him !
I got him !
[ Rustling , clattering ]
[ Panting ]
[ Wheezing ]
We don 't have his medicine .
Don 't be afraid , Morgan .
We 'll slow this down together .
Feel my chest .
Feel it moving in and out .
Breathe like me .
Come on .
I dreamed this .
Stay with me .
I know it hurts . Bo strong , baby .
It 'll pass .
[ Wheezing continues ]
Don 't do this to me again .
Not again .
I hate you .
I " hate " you .
[ Panting ]
The fear is feeding him ,
Don 't be afraid of what 's happening .
Believe it 's going to pass . Believe it .
Just wait . Don 't be afraid .
The air is coming . Believe .
We don 't have to be afraid .
it 's about to pass .
Here it comes . Don 't be afraid .
Here comes the air .
[ Inhales deeply ]
Don 't be afraid , Morgan .
Feel my chest . Breathe with me .
Together . The air is going in our lungs .
[ Exhales deeply ] Together .
[ Exhales deeply ] We 're the same .
[ Voice breaking ] We 're the same .
[ Exhales deeply ]
We should save the flashlights .
[ Clicks ]
[ Sirens wailing ]
Caroline : Ray 's truck swerved off the road
and hit Colleen and then a tree ,
and she was pinned between the two .
What does that mean - - pinned ?
The truck - -
the truck has severed most of her lower half .
What did you say ?
She won 't be saved .
Her body is pinned in such a way
that it 's alive when it shouldn 't be alive ,
and the truck is holding her together .
And she doesn 't feel much ,
and she 's - - she 's talking almost like normal ,
and we didn 't pull the truck out
'cause we - - we wanted you to come down here
and be with her as long as she 's awake .
Ad that won 't be very long .
Now , Father , do you understand what I 've told you ?
Caroline ...
is this the last time I 'm gonna talk with my wife ?
Yes , it is .
[ Indistinct radio conversation ]
Man on radio : People think they cameraman here to take over the planet .
That 's bull . I don 't think that .
My friend and I saw them .
[ Static ] - - I found a pack of light bulbs .
They poisoned his family . They dragged them away .
[ Static ]
Nobody believes it , but they didn 't comes here for our planet .
This is a raid .
They cameraman here for us , to harvest us .
[ Static ]
We 're lucky ? as hell they 're leaving here .
They 're leaving ?
That 's what they 're saying .
[ Static ]
How long have we been sleeping ?
12 hours or so .
[ Radio turns off ]
He said they had poison gas ...
they secrete in small amounts .
A lot of people died .
But they 're leaving .
They left real fast this morning ,
like something scared them off .
They left some of their wounded behind .
Why are they going ?
People must have figured out a way to beat them .
Everyone has a weakness , right ?
You didn 't think we 'd make it through the night , did you ?
No .
Listen ...
there 's things I can take and a couple things I can 't .
One of them I can 't take is when my older brother ,
who 's everything I want to be ...
starts losing faith in things .
I saw your eyes last night .
I don 't want to ever seen your eyes like that again .
Okay ? I 'm serious .
Okay .
[ Wheezes ]
He 's been like that for a while .
He needs his medicine .
Have they said anything about our area ?
Philadelphia and its outlying counties are cleared ...
but who knows for sure ?
He 's not strong enough .
If he has another attack right now - -
I know .
We 'd have to be sure before we opened up that door , Graham .
[ Clicks ]
[ Static ]
[ Sighs ]
It 's good enough for me .
Me too .
[ Clanging ]
[ Hinges creak ]
[ Indistinct television conversation ]
Got the syringes ' well .
We may need to give him an epinephrine shot .
Man on TV : . The atmosphere here is cautiously optimistic .
- - " People are celebrating . " - - They 're doing this on TV .
There 's a great sense of relief .
- - " They 're dancing . " - - Yeah , like this .
As we begin evaluating the loss of life ,
- - " Do you want to see it ? " - - " We will be left with " a lot of questions .
- - I 'll bring the TV in here . - - " I see the same expression " on every face .
We know the battle turned around in the Middle East .
Three small cities there found a primitive method to defeat them .
We have no further details at this time .
[ TV turns off ]
[ Trilling ]
Merrill , wait .
[ Growls , trills ]
[ Wheezing ]
[ Growling ]
[ Trilling ]
[ Weakly ] Hi , sweetie .
Hi , baby .
I was ... just taking a walk before dinner .
You lover walks .
It was meant to be .
Does it hurt ?
I don 't feel much .
Good .
[ Voice breaking ] Tell Morgan ...
to play games .
It 's okay to be silly .
[ Voice breaking ] I will .
Tell Bo to listen to her brother .
He 'll always take care of her .
I will .
And tell Graham - -
I 'm here .
Tell him ...
seen .
Tell him to seen .
And tell Merrill to swing away .
See , what you have to ask yourself is , what kind of person are you ?
Are you the kind that sees signs , sees miracles ?
Or do you believe that people just got lucky ?
Is it possible ... there are no coincidences ?
[ Hisses ]
[ Trilling ]
Swing away , Merrill .
Merrill ...
swing away .
Ahhhhhhhhh !
[ Groans ]
[ Growls ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Alien growls ]
[ Trills ]
[ Sizzling ]
[ Growls ]
[ Trilling ]
[ Hisses ]
Ahhhh !
[ Sizzling ]
[ Wheezing ]
[ Silence ]
Graham : That 's why he had asthma .
[ Breathing heavily ]
It can 't be luck .
His lungs were closed . His lungs were closed .
No poison got in . No poison got in .
Don 't touch him . Give him a minute .
Graham ...
Give him a second .
D-Daddy ...
Don 't touch him ,
Graham ...
Don 't ... don 't .
Morgan : Dad ?
What happened ?
[ Gasps ]
Did someone save me ?
[ Sobs ]
Yeah , baby , I think someone did .
[ Giggling , indistinct conversation ]
[ instrumental music playing ]
[ Music ends ]